[
  {"front": "die Mutter", "back": "mother"},
  {"front": "der Vater", "back": "father"},
  {"front": "die Schwester", "back": "sister"},
  {"front": "der Bruder", "back": "brother"},
  {"front": "die Großmutter", "back": "grandmother"},
  {"front": "der Großvater", "back": "grandfather"},
  {"front": "die Tochter", "back": "daughter"},
  {"front": "der Sohn", "back": "son"},
  {"front": "die Tante", "back": "aunt"},
  {"front": "der Onkel", "back": "uncle"},
  {"front": "die Cousine", "back": "cousin (female)"},
  {"front": "der Cousin", "back": "cousin (male)"},
  {"front": "die Nichte", "back": "niece"},
  {"front": "der Neffe", "back": "nephew"},
  {"front": "die Schwiegermutter", "back": "mother-in-law"},
  {"front": "der Schwiegervater", "back": "father-in-law"},
  {"front": "die Schwägerin", "back": "sister-in-law"},
  {"front": "der Schwager", "back": "brother-in-law"},
  {"front": "der Ehemann", "back": "husband"},
  {"front": "die Ehefrau", "back": "wife"},
  {"front": "die Eltern", "back": "parents"},
  {"front": "die Kinder", "back": "children"},
  {"front": "die Familie", "back": "family"},
  {"front": "die Enkelin", "back": "granddaughter"},
  {"front": "der Enkel", "back": "grandson"},
  {"front": "der Schwarm", "back": "crush"},
  {"front": "die Freundin", "back": "female friend / girlfriend"},
  {"front": "der Freund", "back": "male friend / boyfriend"},
  {"front": "die Verwandten", "back": "relatives"},
  {"front": "die Partnerschaft", "back": "partnership"},
  {"front": "die Ehe", "back": "marriage"},
  {"front": "die Scheidung", "back": "divorce"},
  {"front": "die Großfamilie", "back": "extended family"},
  {"front": "die Kleinfamilie", "back": "nuclear family"},
  {"front": "die Alleinerziehende", "back": "single parent (female)"},
  {"front": "der Alleinerziehende", "back": "single parent (male)"},
  {"front": "das Familienmitglied", "back": "family member"},
  {"front": "die Schwiegertochter", "back": "daughter-in-law"},
  {"front": "der Schwiegersohn", "back": "son-in-law"},
  {"front": "die Stiefmutter", "back": "stepmother"},
  {"front": "der Stiefvater", "back": "stepfather"},
  {"front": "die Stiefschwester", "back": "stepsister"},
  {"front": "der Stiefbruder", "back": "stepbrother"},
  {"front": "das Einzelkind", "back": "only child"},
  {"front": "die Zwillinge", "back": "twins"},
  {"front": "die Adoptivmutter", "back": "adoptive mother"},
  {"front": "der Adoptivvater", "back": "adoptive father"},
  {"front": "die Pflegefamilie", "back": "foster family"},
  {"front": "das Elternteil", "back": "parent"},
  {"front": "die Geschwister", "back": "siblings"},
  {"front": "die Familienangehörigen", "back": "family members"}
]